# Scott Hansen

Fridley, MN 55432 s.hansen18@gmail.com +1 651 357 5757

### Professional Summary or Objective

Having worked 5 years as desktop support, and 6 years as a field technician, I was given an opportunity to change career paths and focus on Cyber Security, something that has always interested me. I am looking forward to a career in Cyber Security and also furthering my knowledge in this field.

I am currently attending a Cybersecurity boot camp put on by the University of Minnesota. We have covered many concepts of both Cybersecurity, but also the fundamentals of computer networking. We have worked with Linux, and Microsoft Windows, Wireshark, Kali Linux, Elk Stack, and Splunk. These projects can be found in my GitHub link.

#### Salary Requirements

I am open to negotiations at the time of hiring.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

# Work Experience

#### **Broadband Technician**

CenturyLink March 2015 to April 2015

#### (2 months)

At Centurylink I was working as a broadband technician, installing DSL, Fiber, and Pots into residential, and small businesses. I also troubleshot and repaired the copper and fiber lines used in providing internet and phone services. Depending on the job, this may have included rewiring or installation of phone jacks. Running new cat5/6 wire and terminating them with rj45/rj11 ends, depending on the use. Finding damaged to the line and repairing it, either on premise or in the field. This career allows me to work independently from other technicians and with little contact from supervisors. Every day I have multiple face to face contacts with our customers, in order to resolve any issues, or to install services, this requires me to translate technical terms and processes to customers who may not know the terms or processes. This part of the job focused mainly on soft skills.

#### **Technical Support Specialist**

YADA SYSTEMS, INC. March 2010 to September 2014

#### (4 years 7 months)

I worked as a help desk technician providing phone support for Axalta's ColorNet Automotive Paint retrieval system software, as well as Axalta's ProfitNet Body Shop management system software and effectively logging the calls. Other support includes hardware troubleshooting of CPU's, printers and custom equipment such as paint scale, and the X-Pert Pour system, and diagnosing any defective hardware. I also directed customers on how to Peer to Peer networks, and install our software in server and client machines (in both a peer to peer setup and domain setup). Logging the calls, and following up

on any unresolved issues. Between calls I worked on setting up an internal help web-page and installing it in a Server 2008 IIS7 environment, learning HTML, Java, CSS, and WIKI syntax as I created the page.

### **Technician**

Army National Guard July 2001 to July 2009

(8 years 1 month)

F4

MOS: 15-T Blackhawk Helicopter Technician

## Education

# **Certificate in Cybersecurity**

University of Minnesota-Twin Cities June 2021 to Present

# A.A. degree in Network Development

Brown College

## Skills

- Computer operation
- Azure
- CSS
- Metasploit
- Cybersecurity
- Active Directory
- Computer hardware
- · Operating systems
- Linux
- Computer networking
- Help desk
- Desktop Support

#### Links

https://github.com/shansen18/BootCamp/blob/main/Readme.md

https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-hansen-cybersecurity-specialist/